Having felt an earnest call to ministry since college, I have been preparing for church ministry through internship opportunities, academic study, voracious reading, intense dialog, and a foray into electronic publishing while simultaneously pursuing a career in software development. Although my primary focus has been church health, including church planting and church strengthening, I have also been gifted in personal counseling and have experience in adoption ministry.

I affirm the <u>Abstract of Principles</u>,¹ the <u>Baptist Faith and Message 2000</u>, the <u>Chicago Statement on Biblical Inerrancy</u>, and the <u>Danvers Statement on Biblical Manhood and Womanhood</u>.

Personal Background

Family

Kathryn Rose (spouse), Vernon Ray, IV (11), Brooklyn Leigh (8), Emma Grace (4), Seth Christopher (1).

Some of our children were adopted in 2011.

Contact

81 McDowell Dr.

Wake Forest, North Carolina 27587 vernon.king@outlook.com | (817) 458–8174

Website: http://www.vernonking.org

Sermons: http://www.vernonking.org/sermons/ Family blog: http://www.adoptedbytheking.com



Education

Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary | Wake Forest, North Carolina

Master of Divinity in Christian Ministry

GPA: 4.0

Southwestern Baptist Theological Seminary | Fort Worth, Texas

Coursework toward Master of Divinity in Missions

GPA: 4.0

Texas A&M University | College Station, Texas

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

GPA: 4.0, summa cum laude

¹Excepting XVII. "The Lord's Day."

Relevant Experience

First Baptist Church | Durham, North Carolina

Pastoral Intern January 2014–May 2014

Met weekly with pastors to discuss ministry in a healthy church:

- Attended elders and members meetings
- Read and reported weekly on ecclesiological texts
- Memorized Ephesians with the other interns

Pillar on the Rock | Ecclesiological Online Magazine

Co-founder and Editor, www.pillarontherock.com

2009-2011

Wrote and edited articles to promote local church health:

- Article reprinted in B&H book, <u>Preach: Theology Meets Practice</u>, by Mark Dever and Greg Gilbert
- Edited 100+ articles; Authored 50+ articles (www.pillarontherock.com/search/label/PJ King)
- Grew the writing team to include six authors

New Song Church | Windhoek, Namibia

Missionary Intern May 2007–August 2007

Residential intern with an IMB missionary team:

- Assisted in the leadership and administration of a weekly outreach serving 150+ students
- Helped host two American youth mission teams for two weeks each
- Provided technical support for church, youth ministries, and camp
- Observed cross-cultural pastoral ministry on a daily basis

Church Background

First Baptist Church | Durham, North Carolina

Member 2013-present

Served in the church in a variety of roles:

- Home Fellowship (small group) co-leader and co-teacher (Fall 2014–present)
- Bible for Life co-teacher, fifth grade boys (Fall 2014–present)
- Bible for Life co-teacher, two year-olds (Fall 2013)

Church of Christ the King (SBC) | Fort Worth, Texas

Member 2010–2012

Considered faithful to the community and participated in *ad hoc* duties:

- Deacon candidate (moved out of state soon after nomination)
- Organized greeter and security rotations
- Administered web technologies for the church

Portland Avenue Baptist Church | Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

Member 2008–2009

Sacrificially served while discerning future ministry goals:

- Interim College and Career Director
- Break-out teacher for youth ministry
- Assumed temporary guardianship for twin teenage girls from the youth group

Trinity Baptist Church | Norman, Oklahoma

Attended 2007–2008

Actively participated before planned move out of town.

First Baptist Church | Bryan, Texas

Member 2003–2007

Engaged in ministry during full tenure of college:

- Served as a youth leader
- Participated in college discipleship programs

First Baptist Church | Woodway, Texas

Member 1992–2003

Raised by my parents to be a faithful member:

- Baptized by Michael Toby, 1992
- Served on student leadership team during high school
- Served in numerous domestic mission trips and foreign missions to
- Served in youth mission trips to Spain, Morocco, and Namibia
- Counseled as a college leader for youth camps and mission trips

Professional History

Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary | Wake Forest, North Carolina

Software Developer May 2013-present

FTS International | Fort Worth, Texas

Lead Software Developer May 2011–January 2013

Led a team of five engineers and served as a point of contact with management

Deloitte Consulting | Dallas, Texas

Software Consultant, Homeland Security

January 2011-May 2011

FIS | Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

Senior Programmer Analyst Programmer Analyst II October 2009–November 2010 September 2007–October 2009

Hewlett-Packard | College Station, Texas

ASIC Intern May 2006–May 2007

Texas A&M University | College Station, Texas

Peer Teacher, Department of Computer Science

September 2004-May 2006

References

Nathan Finn, Ph.D.

Elder, First Baptist Church, Durham

Associate Professor, Historical Theology and Baptist Studies, Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary (919) 280-4309

nfinn@sebts.edu

Benjamin H. Arbour, Ph.D.

Mentor and Friend (979) 574-1300 benarbour03@yahoo.com

Andy Winn, M.Div.

Associate Pastor, First Baptist Church, Durham (919) 452-1427 andy.winn@fbcdurham.org

Ryan Hutchinson, M.Div.

Elder, First Baptist Church, Durham

Executive Vice President for Operations, Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary
(919) 761-2200

hutchinson@sebts.edu

David Jacks

Lead Pastor, Church of Christ the King (817) 395-2180 davidjacks1967@gmail.com